Zierlin, Abe Collection of ILGWU Convention Photographs 6036/093 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Abe Zierlin Collection of ILGWU Convention Photographs
1953-1962
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Zierlin, Abba (Abe)
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
6036/093 P
0.78 cubic feet
0.8 linear ft.
Photographs.
9269246
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
M. Clark, January 14, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 24, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
9269246
- Thirty First Convention - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Convention Auditorium, Atlantic City, N.J. -- May 23-June 1, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Delegation - 28th Convention of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- May 18 to 26, 1953 - Chicago, Ill. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 30th Convention - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, A.F.L.-C.I.O., Miami Beach, Florida -- May 11 to 19, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Twenty-ninth Convention - ILGWU - A.F.L.-C.I.O., Atlantic City, NJ -- May 10-18, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 30th Convention - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union-A.F.L.-C.I.O., Miami Beach, Florida -- May 11 to 19, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Thirty-First Convention - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Convention Auditorium, Atlantic City, N.J. -- May 23-June 1, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Opening Session - 28th Convention of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- May 18 to 26, 1953 - Civic Opera House, Chicago, Ill. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Second Session, 28th Convention of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- May 18 to 26, 1953 - Chicago, Ill. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Thirty-First Convention - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - Convention Auditorium, Atlantic City, NJ -- May 23-June 1, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Twenty-ninth Convention - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - Convention Hall, Atlantic City, NJ -- May 10-18, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)